丑陋裸男在装饰他的树
Ugly Naked Guy is decorating his tree.
天啊 你该瞧瞧他圣诞球的大小
You should see the size of his Christmas balls!
你们今年给管理员多少红包？
How much did you tip the super?
是啊，我们打算给50 不过我们不想显得比你们小器
We were gonna give 50,but we don't wanna look bad.
今年我们送他自己做的饼干
This year we made him cookies.
那就包25块好了
And 25 it is.
你们送他饼干？
You gave cookies?
给钱太见外了
Money is so impersonal.
饼干表示我们关心他
Cookies says someone cares.
好吧，我们没钱 但饼干也能表达这个意思
We're broke,but cookies do say that.
我了解
I can see that.
曾有盘巧克力糕告诉我一首打油诗
A plate of brownies told me a limerick.
菲比，请问你 那些是“搞笑的”巧克力糕吗？
Pheebs,let me ask you something. Were these "funny" brownies?
并不特别啊
Not especially.
但我觉得里面有大麻
But I think they had pot in them.
两位，你们还送了谁饼干？
So who else did you tip with cookies?
邮差，管理员…
The mailman,the super....
还有那个送报纸的
And the newspaper delivery guy.
天哪
Oh,my God.
怎么了？
What?
你们可能不会高兴看到这个
You're not gonna like this.
天哪，还有饼干糊在运动版呢
These are cookies smashed to the sports section.
看，在我的字谜那里也是
He did my crossword puzzle.
对，但是错误百出，除非 横十四的“格什温音乐剧”…
Yeah,but not very well,unless 14 across,"Gershwin musical"...
是叫“咬我，咬我，咬我”
...actually is "Bite me,bite me,bite me."
六人行 第2季 第09集 菲比的爸爸
The One With Phoebe's Dad
真不敢相信圣诞节又到了
I can't believe it's Christmas already.
我们才刚吃完了感恩节火鸡…
One day you're eating turkey,the next thing you know...
转眼呢 现在又到了圣人跳跃和呆鹅下蛋的圣诞节
...Iords are a-leaping and geese are a-laying.
所以每年的这个时候 鹅才会感觉到很轻松
Which is why geese are so relaxed this time of year.
各位
Hey,guys.
瑞秋
Hey,Rach.
我买了一个小礼物给你
I got you a little present.
我来拆
I'll open it.
是“机灵鬼”
It's a Slinky!
记得吗？
Remember?
走下楼梯，单独或成双
Walks downstairs Alone or in pairs
大家都知道是…
Everyone knows it's
只是一个大弹簧
Just a big spring.
好吧，你还在生我的气 就为了…
You're still mad because of the whole
那张不跟我在一起的理由的可恶单子？
Horrible list of reasons not to be with me?
从现在起我们称那为 “不幸的事件”怎么样？
How about we just call it the "unfortunate incident"?
甘瑟，你家里有没有楼梯？
Hey,Gunther. You got stairs in your place?
去疯吧
Go nuts.
各位
Hey,guys.
袋子里有什么？
What's in the bag?
只是些礼物啦
Some presents.
快拿出来瞧瞧啊
Come on,show us what you bought.
其实你很想的
You know you want to.
好吧，你们看 这是班送给我父母的相框
This is a picture frame from Ben to my parents.
很可爱
Oh,that's cute.
“她的”跟“她的”毛巾 给苏珊跟凯洛
Some "Hers" and "Hers" towels for Susan and Carol.
还有，买了这件衬衫给妈
And I got this blouse for Mom.
罗斯，好漂亮哦
Ross,that is gorgeous!
瞧瞧这些假徽章
Look at these authentic fake metals!
妈会得到“最佳服装奖”…
Mom's gonna be voted "best dressed"...
…在假的军校里
...at the make-believe military academy!
圣诞前夕的前夕快乐
Happy "Christmas Eve" Eve.
我的天哪，这哪儿来的？
Oh,my God! Where did you get this?
梅西百货三楼，家饰部
Macy's,third floor,home furnishings.
这是我爸爸
This is my father!
这是我爸爸的照片
This is a picture of my dad!
菲比，那是相框附送的相片
That's the guy that comes in the frame.
不，这是我爸爸 好，我拿给你们看
No,it's my dad. I'll show you.
菲比，我以为你爸在牢里
I thought your dad was in prison.
不，那是我继父
No,that's my stepdad.
我真正的爸 是我出生以前就跑了的那个
My real dad's the one that ran out on us before I was born.
你怎么会没上过奥普拉的访谈啊？
How have you never been on Oprah?
瞧，这就是他
Look,see? This is him.
我妈在死前给了我这张照片 同一个人
My mother gave me this picture before she died. Same guy!
这是一张相框模特儿…
This is a picture of the frame guy...
…跟一只牧羊犬站在浅蓝背景前的照片
...posing in front of a blue screen with a collie.
那不是蓝背景，那是…
It's not a blue screen. It's just....
也许那天万里晴空吧
Maybe it was just really clear that day.
我得跟我外婆谈一谈
Okay,I have to talk to my grandmother.
等一下，菲比
Wait a minute,honey!
我在设法 弄我老板的前任老婆上床
I'm trying to get my boss's ex-wife to sleep with me.
菲比有问题时大家都洗耳恭听
But when Phoebe has a problem,everyone's all ears!
艾斯特・利文斯顿
Esther Livingston.
死了
Gone!
嗨，小熊
Hi,Pooh.
外婆，你在干嘛？
Hi,Gram. What you doing?
我在更新电话簿
Just updating the phone book.
外婆？
Gram?
我可以再看一次 我爸的照片吗？
Can I see the pictures of my dad again?
当然，当然了
Sure,sure.
为什么？
How come?
我只是突然想看一看
Just,you know,to see him.
好，来
Sure. Here.
这是你爸站在草地上的照片
This is the one of your father in a meadow.
他…帮一个小男孩放风筝
And helping a little boy fly a kite.
这一张是他的毕业典礼
And here he is at a graduation.
再一张的毕业典礼
Another graduation.
再来一张毕业典礼
他真的是我爸爸吗？
Is this really my father?
他真的是你爸…？
Is it really your fa?
天哪，他当然是
Well,of course it is.
我闻到烟味了，也许是因为有人的裤子着火了（说谎）
I smell smoke. Maybe because someone's pants are on fire!
我们两个当祖孙这么多年了…
In all the years we've been grandmother and granddaughter...
…你从没有对我撒过谎
...you've never lied.
好吧，他不是你爸爸 他只是一个相框里的男人
All right,that's not your father. It's a picture of a guy in a frame.
天啊
Oh,God.
那是你妈的主意
It was your mother's idea.
她不想让你知道谁是你爸…
She didn't want you to know your real father...
…因为他的离去让你妈很伤心
... because he hurt her so much.
我本来也不想跟着她骗你
I didn't want to do it.
可是她死了 那样跟她争辩就太难了
But then she died and it was harder to argue with her.
不是不可能，只是更难
Not impossible,but harder.
那他不是一个有名的树医？
All right. So he's not a famous tree surgeon?
他也不住在 没有电话的缅甸茅屋里头？
And I guess he doesn't live in a hut in Burma where there's no phones?
我听说他在纽约州 某个地方当药剂师
Last I heard,he was a pharmacist somewhere upstate.
那没有道理
That makes no sense.
村民干嘛去崇拜一个 药剂师呢？
Why would the villagers worship a pharmacist?
亲爱的
Honey.
反正呢，我所知道的就这么多
Anyway,that's all I know.
还有…
That...
…跟这个
...and this.
这…
This...
…是真正的他了
...is the real him.
我记得我爸爸 他穿了一身火红的衣服…
I remember my father all dressed up in the red suit...
…黑色的大靴子 还有漆皮皮带…
...the big black boots and the patent leather belt...
…在楼下鬼鬼崇崇的 他不想被任何人发现…
...sneaking around downstairs. He didn't want us to see him...
…可是他醉得摇摇晃晃 然后撞东撞西把大家都吵醒
... but he'd be drunk,so he'd crash into something and wake everybody up.
听起来不像是个快乐的圣诞节
That doesn't sound like a very merry Christmas.
谁说是圣诞节来着？
Who said anything about Christmas?
有没有菲比的消息？
Anyone hear from Phoebe yet?
没有
No,nothing.
希望她没事
I hope she's okay.
是呀，我完全了解她的处境
I know exactly what she's going through.
你怎么会完全了解她的处境？
How do you know that?
她告诉我们的嘛
She told us.
莫妮卡，你买了什么？
What do you got there,Monica?
派对要用的东西
Stuff for the party.
你们还在这里干嘛 你们不是该去买礼物了吗？
Aren't you guys supposed to be shopping?
你们礼物还没买好吗？
You didn't buy presents yet?
明天就是圣诞夜了 你们要怎么办？
Tomorrow's Christmas Eve! What are you gonna do?
你一定要像粘土动画里的人物那样说话吗？
Don't you have to be Claymation to say that?
对了，莫妮卡 我想邮差不欣赏你的饼干
I don't think the mailman liked your cookies.
这是你妈寄来的装饰品
The ornaments your mom sent.
说不定他喜欢我的饼干 只是他嫌少了
Maybe the mailman liked the cookies. We just didn't give him enough.
莫妮卡，鸽子都学得比你快
Monica,pigeons learn faster than you.
瑞秋
Hey,Rach.
我想我知道 怎么样让你好过点了
I think I know what will make you feel better.
你列张关于我的清单如何？
How about you make a list about me?
什么？算了吧，罗斯 我怎么会…
Forget it. I'm not gonna stand here...
…去列一张关于你的…
...and make a list
好，你爱发牢骚…
Okay,you're whiny...
…爱钻牛角尖 没有安全感…
...you are obsessive,you are insecure...
…你根本就没种
...you're gutless.
你从来不知道怎么把握时机
You don't ever just "seize the day."
你暗恋我一年 结果你什么都没做
You liked me for a year and you didn't do anything about it.
还有，你头发涂了太多发胶了
And you wear too much of that gel in your hair.
瞧…
See,there....
你照我说的做了
All right,you did what I said.
对呀，你知道吗？ 你说得对，我觉得好多了
And you know what? You're right. I do feel better.
谢了，罗斯
Thank you,Ross.
是的，在奥尔巴尼（纽约州首府），麻烦你查一查弗兰克布菲的电话
Yeah,in Albany. Could I have the number of Frank Buffay?
伊萨卡（纽约州）呢？
Okay. In lthaca?
好吧，萨拉托加（纽约州）呢？
All right,Saratoga?
尤蒂卡（纽约州）呢？
Oneonta?
好吧，你知道吗？ 你没有资格自称查号台
You know what? You shouldn't call yourself lnformation!
外婆 请问这是不是你的真姓名？
Hello,Grandma. If that is,in fact,your real name.
好了，小熊，别跟我生气了
Come on now,Pooh. Don't still be mad at me.
进行得怎么样了？ 不太好
-How's it going? -Not so good.
纽约州蛮大的，他蛮小的 你自己算吧
Upstate's pretty big. He's pretty small. You do the math.
我想没找到他对你还比较好
Well,I think you're better off without him.
我知道他是你爸爸
Oh,honey,I know he's your daddy.
但是对我而言…
But to me,he's still the irresponsible creep...
…他是那个让你妈怀孕 又偷她的车子，不负责的混球
...who locked up your mom and stole her Gremlin.
我知道啊 只是想知道他是谁而已
I know. I just wanted to know who he was,you know?
是啊，我知道
Yeah,I know.
我说我不知道他住在哪里…
I wasn't completely honest with you when I said I didn't know...
…是有点骗你
...exactly where he lived.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
他住在中城市罗瑞街74号
He lives at 74 Laurel Drive in Middletown.
要是看到奶品皇后冰淇淋店，就过头了
If you hit the Dairy Queen,you've gone too far.
开我的车去吧
You can take my cab.
谢了
Thank you.
我的计程车别让别人开啊 知道了
-Nobody else drives that cab. -Got it.
我要见到我爸爸了
I'm gonna see my dad!
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧，祝我好运了，爷爷 （爱因斯坦的照片）
Wish me luck,Grandpa.
菲比开计程车来了吗？
Phoebe here with the cab yet?
来了，那是一辆隐形车
Yeah,she brought the invisible cab.
上车吧
Hop in!
她最好快一点 商店七点就关门了
She'd better get here. The stores close at 7.
我想菲比去她爸那儿 大概两个小时…
It'll be two hours to Phoebe's dad's house...
…他们见面，聊天 交换生活故事
...they'll meet,chat,swap life stories.
甚至她会说她是个埃及奴隶，我们还是有时间的
Even if she tells the one where she's an Egyptian slave, we'll have time.
她来了
Hey,here she comes!
你们相信吗？
Can you believe this?
再两个小时我就有爸爸了
In,like,two hours I'm gonna have a dad.
是呀，大事哦
Yeah,big stuff!
对呀，走吧
Okay,let's go!
好，你来拿着这个
Here,you have to hold this.
左刹车，右油门？
"Brake,left. Gas,right"?
对，我的小抄
That's my cheat sheet.
安全带呢？ 你那边没有了
-Where's my seat belt? -There isn't one.
被救护人员剪开了
The paramedics had to cut through it.
告诉我嘛，拜托…
Come on,just tell me. Please,please!
这是第十六次了： 不，我不认为你钻牛角尖
For the 16th time: No,I do not think you're obsessive!
天哪，这里怎么这么热啊 麻烦把暖气关小
-It's hot in here! -Rach,get the heat.
罗斯，把暖气关小
Ross,turn the heat down,please?
两个之间是有差别…
The difference between obsessive
罗斯，暖气
Ross,the heat!
好，暖气…还说我钻牛角尖？
Okay! Heat,heat,heat! And I'm the obsessive one?
好吧，往这边是开
This way is on.
往这边是…
So this is...
…关
...off.
你是否把暖气弄坏了？
Did you just break the radiator?
没有，我不过是转了开关…
No,I was turning the knob and...
…结果就掉了
... here it is.
那就装回去啊
Well,put it back!
装不回去了
It won't go back.
我打电话给管理员
I'll call the super.
来，我来试试
Here,let me try.
对了 我忘了你融合金属的能力了
That's right. I forgot about your ability to fuse metal.
嘿，真是好笑的表亲…
Hey,it's Funny's cousin...
…不好笑
... Not Funny!
崔格先生？
Hi,Mr. Treeger?
我是楼上的瑞秋格林
It's Rachel Greene from upstairs.
对，有人弄坏 我们暖气的开关了…
Yes,somebody broke our knob on the radiator...
…我们这里好热
...and it's really hot in here.
对，热到可以烤饼干了
Yes,it's hot enough to bake cookies.
你想你能在六点以前换好吗？
Could we have a new one by 6?
什么？不，不，星期二 我们等不到那个时候
Tuesday? We can't wait until Tuesday.
我们今晚有派对
We're having a party tonight.
好吧，给他小费
Okay,tip the man.
不，不喜欢我们的饼干就算了吧
If he doesn't like our cookies,too bad.
我才不要任人勒索呢
I won't be blackmailed.
这里有点热…
Look,if it gets a little warm...
…就改成主题派对好了
...it can be a theme party.
这下有主题了： “请进，来当培根火腿吧”
Here's a theme: "Come on in,live like bacon!"
就是这里了
This is it!
74号
Seventy-four.
长途跋涉为这个
So that's what this is for!
就是这里了 我要见到我爸爸了
This is it. I'm gonna meet my dad.
这真是前所未有的大事
This is like the biggest thing ever.
说得没错
Sure is.
好了，我要进去了
Here I go. I'm going in.
好啊
All right!
一切顺利哦
Good luck,Pheebs.
好了，我走了
Here I go.
我走了
我要走了
I'm going.
欢迎光临我们的热带圣诞派对
Welcome to our tropical Christmas party.
外套，毛衣，长裤跟衬衫 请放在卧室里面
Put your coats,sweaters,pants and shirts in the bedroom.
我在冒汗，所以看不出来…
It's hard to tell because I'm sweating...
…但我完全遵照 瓶上指示的用量
... but I use exactly what the gel bottle says.
一颗豆子大小的份量而已 那怎么会太多呢？
An amount about the size of a pea. How can that be too much?
冰块？
Ice?
谁要冰块？拿张餐巾
Ice? Ice squares anyone? Take a napkin.
莫妮卡？莫妮卡？
Monica!
你的客人都快变成牛肉干了
Your guests are turning into jerky.
真的？我觉得舒服得很
Really? I'm perfectly comfortable.
排队呀，兄弟，换我了
Hey! Get in line,buddy. I was next.
崔格先生
Mr. Treeger.
你说有派对啊？
You said there was a party.
欢迎光临我们的桑拿聚会
Well,hey,welcome to our sauna.
很热吗？我从来不觉得热
Is it hot? My body always stays cool.
说不定是因为我皮太厚了
Probably because I have so much skin.
乳酪
Hey,cheese!
好吧，好吧，机会来了 莫妮卡，给他现金
Here's the chance. Monica,give him cash.
瑞秋，把你的耳环给他 快啊，任何东西都给他
Rachel,give him your earrings. Something. Anything!
不，我不屈服
No,I will not cave.
对，我也是
I'm with Mon.
好吧… 你说我从不把握机会？
All right. You know how you say I never seize the day?
他虽然是你们的管理员 我也要把握一下
Even though he's your super,I'm seizing.
崔格先生？
Mr. Treeger?
这里是50块钱，圣诞快乐
Here is $50. Merry Christmas.
我没有准备你的礼物
I didn't get you anything.
送你5块钱好了
Here's five back.
不，那是你的圣诞红包
No,that's your Christmas tip.
你认为你可不可以 现在把暖气给修好？
Do you think there's a chance you can fix that radiator now?
没办法，我已经说过了…
No can do. Like I told the girl...
…星期二才拿得到新的开关
... I can't get a knob until Tuesday.
罗斯？
Ross?
看来他在玩棒球哦
He's playing baseball.
你要说硬式棒球吗？
You mean hardball?
随便啦
Whatever.
你打算怎么样呢？
What you gonna do?
抱歉，我还要努力一下
Excuse me. I'm seizing.
崔格先生？
Mr. Treeger?
我再给你五十
Here's another 50.
光明节（犹太人的节日）快乐
Happy Hanukkah.
这样我们是不是 可以拿到新的开关了呢？
Will this help with the knob-getting?
不行 那家店星期二才会开门
No,the place is not open till Tuesday.
我的发音不标准吗？
Am I not saying it right?
你真的喜欢我的饼干吗？
So you really did like my cookies?
是呀，那好温暖哦 真的表示你的关心
Yeah,they were so personal. It really showed you cared.
把握得好…
Nice seizing...
…发胶男
...gel boy.
这是w寄生，没错吧？
Is this mistletoe?
不，那个叫…
No,that....
…叫罗勒
That is basil.
如果是w寄生，我就要亲你了
If it was mistletoe,I was gonna kiss you.
不，那还是罗勒
No,it's still basil.
火炉上烤栗子
Chestnuts roasting on an open fire
雪人在啃你的鼻子
Jack Frost nipping at your nose
你走到哪里啊？ 信箱
-How far did you get? -Mailbox.
有进步了
All right,we're getting closer.
菲比，你怎么了？
What's going on?
其实原因很多啦
It's just like a whole mess of stuff.
昨天，我爸爸他还是一个 名闻遐迩的缅甸树医
Like yesterday,my dad was this famous Burma tree-surgeon guy.
可是他现在 却变成一个药剂师了…
And you know,now he's a pharmacist guy and....
或许他是一个 很酷的药剂师也说不定
Well,maybe he's this really cool pharmacist guy.
对，或许，对 然后我会跑去敲他的门…
Yeah,maybe! And I'll knock on the door...
…他会拥抱我，我会有个爸爸
...and he'll hug me,and I'll have a dad!
然后大家都会亲切地对待我…
I'll go to his pharmacy and everyone will be nice to me...
…因为我是弗兰克的女儿
... because,you know,I'm Frank's daughter.
那就快去敲门哪
So why not go knock?
如果他没有那么棒呢？
Because,I mean,what if he's not this great-dad guy?
如果他还是那个 抛妻弃子的浑球呢？
What if he's still the dirtbag who ran out on my mom and us?
你知道吗？
You know what?
我这个礼拜 已经失去一个假爸爸了
I've already lost a fake dad this week.
我不想再失去一个真的爸爸
I don't think I'm ready to lose a real one.
菲比，没关系啦 你已经跨了一大步了
Pheebs,that's okay. You took a big step today.
有一天当你准备好的时候 你就会越过那片篱笆了
Someday,when you're ready,you'll make it past the hedges.
那个时候他会有幸得到你
And when you do,he'll be lucky to have you.
你们…
You guys....
抱歉，你们来不及购物了
Sorry about your shopping.
没关系，会有办法的
Oh,that's okay. We'll figure something out.
我知道你不要进去…
I know you're not going in there...
…不过你想我可不可以进去 跟他借一下洗手间？
... but you think it's okay if I go in and use his bathroom?
没关系，算了
That's fine,never mind.
酷耶，下雪了
Cool,snow!
像空白的画布
Kind of like a blank canvas.
该死，这里面好热啊
Ho-ho-ho-holy crap,is it hot in here!
介意我把暖气关小吗？
You mind if I turn the heat down?
我们怎么都没想到呢
We could have used that kind of thinking earlier!
菲比，结果怎么样？
So,Pheebs,how did it go?
我没有办法进去
Oh,I couldn't go in.
好可惜喔 你还好吗？
-Honey,I'm sorry. -Are you okay?
好，没关系 因为我知道他在哪儿
Yeah,it's okay,because I know he's there.
现在只要那样就够了
So that's enough for now.
各位，过了十二点了 祝大家圣诞快乐
Hey,it's after midnight! Merry Christmas,everyone!
圣诞快乐
Oh,right! Merry Christmas!
开关坏了…
The knob was broken...
…所以我从下面关掉了 希望不会有问题
...so I turned it off from underneath. I hope that's all right.
谢谢
Thanks.
就剩下乔伊和钱德的礼物了
I guess that just leaves the gifts from Joey and Chandler.
瑞秋，送你的
Rach,these are for you.
汽车雨刷
Wiper blades!
我连车都没有
I don't even have a car.
对呀，但加上这个汽车芳香剂 你会以为你有
No,but with this new-car smell,you'll think you do!
菲比，换你了
Okay,Pheebs,your turn.
马桶纸垫啊
Toilet-seat covers!
我去加油的时候 你们就去买这个吗？
Is that what you did while I got gas?
你们两个真好！
You guys!
至于罗斯…
And for Ross...
…甜食先生
... Mr. Sweet Tooth.
你们送我一瓶可乐？
You got me a cola drink?
还有柠檬味的
And a lemon-lime!
简直太…太厚礼了吧 我应该再送你们一件毛衣
Well,this is too much! I feel like I should get you another sweater.
还有一个很有价值的…
And last,but not least....
加纹让你更有快感（安全套）
They're ribbed for your pleasure!